<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="lesson_names">
        <item>Islamic Expansion </item>
        <item>King Leopold </item>
        <item>Mansa Musa </item>
        <item>Willie Lynch Letter </item>
        <item>Essay For Augustus </item>
        <item>Activists of 60s </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="lesson_contents">
        <item>&lt;b>The Islamic culture&lt;/b> began in Arabian Peninsula, the region where Mecca is located and a place where Mohammad, the prophet popularly known and referred to as messenger by Muslims was born. In the year 570, he began to receive what the Muslims today regard as divine revelations delivered through angel Gabriel which later formed the writings of the Muslim scripture, Quran. The believers of Islam agree that the teachings of Islam were verbally communicated to Mohammad by God identified as Allah in Arabic language which should be the spoken language of Mohammad.
            &lt;p>
            Before the emergence of Islamic culture in Arabian Peninsula. There has been already existing religious practices and traditions and belief system such as Christianity and probably Hellenism.., so the new teaching of Mohammad seemed to be disturbing and luring people into adopting the new culture of Islam ,this must have acted against the Grecians that it prompted the fiercest battle at al-Yarmuk, a battle between the Greeks and the believersof Islam which became so brutal and involving both men and women participation  .About 24,000 Muslims fought the 70,000 Greeks and by the help of Allah, they gain victory even as the battle reached as far as Palestine, Antioch ,Aleppo, Mesopotamia and Armenia.
            &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            This war or battle between Muslims and non-Muslims helped the spread of Islam overseas and in Europe, it entered into the communities of non-Muslims including southern Spain where they made agreement with Theodemir, the Christian king of that region ,agreement which included not to harass Theodemir nor demote him from power, theMuslims also vowed not to take away sacred objects from the realm although these were based on certain condition such as; if he (theodemir) will not give shelter to fugitives nor to their enemies .
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Theodemir was in addition, given the condition to pay one dinar every year, four measures of wheat,barley, concentrated fruit juice, vinegar, honeyetc. These conditions were applied to each of his men and slaves were required to pay half of the amount of all the things imposed on the freemen .
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            In addition to the aforesaid, Mohammad also introduced a system that practiced granting of gifts which later became regularized and institutionalized, this idea of granting gifts turned into stipends paid to the people who devoted themselves in serving as Islamic warriors to enable the spread of Islam. The stipends were also granted to some other people ,for instance , the nobles within Persia region provided they cooperate with the Muslims  .Many were required to embrace Islam in order to receive their stipends ,it was indeed a good strategic way of recruiting people to accept the belief of Islam and of course many who didn’t have enough to sustain themselves with -would consider receiving the stipends an opportunity to enjoy a well fed and good living .
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            The conclusion is that Mohammad must have envisioned the future of Islam and had a planed and well organized strategy to execute his mission ,but on the other hand interfered with the existing authorities and religions during the early spread of Islam .Most people who had nothing but just life became the converted mass through wars/conquest and  the system of stipends paid for accepting Islam and this idea played a huge role in the expansion of Islam .
             &lt;/p>
        </item>
        <item>&lt;b>KING LEOPOLD 2 to the Missionaries&lt;/b>\n\n
            &lt;p>
            Here is the letter written by King Leopold second of Belgium to the missionaries traveling to Congo in 1883 to spread Christianity. King Leopold was in fact another Hitler from Europe, he was so murderous and evil, but no one talks about him and his evil deeds. Read from an exempt, his instructions to the priests he sent to Congo, Since Congo was part of their share of the African nation after the meeting ‘ scrambled for Africa’ a meeting held in Berlin for the destruction of black people and their nations.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Reverend fathers and dear compatriots, the task asked of you to accomplish is very delicate and demands much tact and diplomacy. Fathers, you are going to preach the gospel, but your preaching must be inspired by first the interests of the Belgian government states.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            The main goal of your mission in the Congo is not to teach the negroes the knowledge of God because they already know him, they talk and they commit themselves to their God, they know that killing stealing adultery and blasphemy are not good, your role essentially will be to easily facilitate the task of the administrative and industrial personnel. that is to say, you will interpret the gospel in a way to protect and serve the interests of Belgium in that part of the world, to do so, you will see that our savages express no interest in the riches that their soil possesses in order that they do not want them, thus they be not involved in murderous competition with us and dream to live a luxurious life.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Your knowledge of the scriptures will help us to use special text that recommends the infidels to love poverty such as beatitude which says ‘blessed are the poor for theirs is the Kingdom of heaven’ ‘it is impossible for the rich to enter the Kingdom of God’. You will do all that you can to cause them to fear being rich in order that they may enter the Kingdom of heaven, from time to time keep them from rebelling and keep them in fear,  you will use violence to teach them to endure long suffering, in fact to endure anything even when they are insulted or beaten by your compatriots. You will teach them that whosoever uses vengeance is not a child of God and cause them to follow the example of this sense who turned the other cheek. You will take them away from anything or any act that gives them the courage to confront us. I am alluding myself here to their magic, that is; juju or voodoo. {the term alluding means; drawing attention to} they should not feel like abandoning their juju and you will do your best to take them away at the same time your action will be essentially on the young people that they might not rebel. If the commandments of the father are in conflict with what the parents teach the child should learn to obey what the missionaries teach him because he is the father of his soul. We must force them into submission and obedience. Dear compatriots, these are some of the principles you must apply, you will find many more in the book that will be given to you at the end of this session teach these folly in an African style in order that they adopt it easily and be kept submissive to the white colonists.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Make them always meditate on ‘blessed be those who weep for theirs is the Kingdom of heaven convert the Africans always by means of the whip, keep their wives in submission for nine months so they can walk for you graciously but acquire from them an offering of recognition to you goats chicken eggs each time you visit the village avoid by all means the Blacks becoming rich
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Cause them to sing each and every day say that is impossible for a rich man to enter into heaven
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Make them pay tithes each Sunday for church, utilize this money that is intended for the poor for our own business investments. Institute a system of confession which will make you good detective in order to denounce and put down every black man which has a spirit of rebellion against the system , teach them that their statues are works of the devil, confiscate them and fill our museums with them, teach them to forget about their heroes in order to worship and give praise to ours ,don’t give a seat to a black man when they come to see you, at the most just give him a cigarette
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Do not invite him to break bread with you even if he gives you a chicken every time you go to see him, consider All Blacks as little children and require them to refer to you as Father all day long.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            My dear compatriots if you apply to the letter all this the interests of Belgian in Congo will be protected for many centuries. I thank you
             &lt;/p>
            &lt;b>King Leopold 2 of Belgian&lt;/b>
        </item>
        <item>&lt;b>Mansa Musa&lt;/b> seemed to be an individual who never cared to take opinion of others and would stick to his decisions. An instance would be the time when he refused to meet the sultan of Cairo because he did not want to mix anything else with his pilgrimage .The Catalan Atlas ,1375, reveals a map from Spain drawn in the year 1375 by Abraham Cresques depicting Musa and his wealth thereby acknowledging him to be the `Lord of the Black People of Mali` and a noble king of all the land  .
             &lt;p>
            It would make sense to sum the whole thing up by noting the fact that Musa`s wealth was not confined within his environment, he lived his life giving to the needy and probably those who are not in need, hence winning their heart which of course everyone who witnessed or those who had received from him would consider his wealth so huge and immeasurable.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Being rich may not necessarily mean having money in abundance, it could mean more than having property and being intelligent, having the knowledge of life and its worth as well as helping others who are in struggle. Mansa Musa was a known emperor of Mali (1312-1327 BC) whose wealth had been confirmed by many authors and individuals who witnessed as of the time he reigned.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Mansa Musa was a devout Muslim and in the year 1324 he made a historical trip to Mecca. As a devout Muslim in conjunction with his influence and power, he built libraries and several mosques as well as supporting education in the Quran. It is said that his wealth was a result of his country`s vast resources which he left behind after his death and invaders dominated it just about two generations thereafter .
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            In spite of his extravagance, he did not neglect the presence of others around him. He offered them so many gifts as much as he could and according toAl-Umari, the historian from Damascus, Syria, Mansa Musa, prior to his visit to Mecca, arrived in Cairo and there he gave away many gifts of gold through which the people of Cairo made incalculable profits from it.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            The Huffington Post’’Mansa Musa Of Mali Named World`s Richest Man Of All Time; Gates And Buffet Also Make List’’ The Huffington Post.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            http://www.huffintonpost.com/2012/10/17/mansamusa-world-richest-man-all-time_n_1973840.html.
             &lt;/p>
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;b>TO MAKE A SLAVE: By WILLIE LYNCH &lt;/b>\n\n
             &lt;p>p>Here is a speech delivered by Willie Lynch in the United States in 1712. Willie Lynch was a man from West Indies, a slave owner who owned a large plantation. The word ‘Lynching’ was coined up after his last name Lynch, which means; to kill someone by hanging or without trial. He had used a simple method of controlling the blacks during slavery, but his method was too diabolical. Below is an exempt from his speech as he addressed the white slave masters in Virginia, United States.
                 &lt;/p>&lt;p>Gentlemen;
            &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            greet you here on the Bank of the James River in the year of our Lord 1712. First, I should thank you the gentleman of the colony of Virginia for bringing me here, I am here to help you solve some of your problems with slaves,and your invitation reached me in my modest plantation in the West Indies where I have experimented with some of the newest and still the oldest method for control of slaves. Ancient Rome would envy us if my program is implemented.As ourboat sailed South on the James River named for our illustrious King James whose Bible we cherish. I saw enough to know that our problem is not unique, why Rome used ropes and woods as crosses for standing human bodies along the old highways in great number, you are here using the tree and the rope on occasion.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            I caught the whiff of a dead slave hanging from a tree a couple of miles back.You are losing valuable stock by hangings, you are having uprisings, slaves are running away, your crops are sometimes left in the field too long for maximum profit, you suffer occasionally fires, your animals are killed.Gentlemen, you know what your problems are, I do not need to elaborate.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Iam not here to enumerate your problems; I am here to introduce you to a method of solving them.
            &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            In my bag, I have a foolproof method for controlling your slaves. I guarantee every one of you that if installed, it will control the slaves for at least 300 years. My method is simple, any member of your family or any overseer can use it.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            I have outlined several differences among the slaves, I take these differences and make them bigger. I use fear, distrust, and envy for control purposes. These methods have worked on my modest plantation In the West Indies and it will work throughout the South. Take this simple little list of differences and think about them, in the top of my list is Age, but it is only there because it starts with an A. the second is color orshade, there is intelligence, size, sex, size of plantation, attitude of owner, whether the slaves live in the Valley, East or West,North or South, have a fine or coarse hair,tall or short.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Now that you have a list of differences, I shall give you an outline of action but before that, I assure you that distrust is stronger than trust, and envy is stronger than adulation, respect or admiration. The black slaves after receiving this indoctrination shall carry on and will become self-refueling and self-generating for hundreds of years, maybe thousands.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Don’t forget you must pitch the old black vs the young black males, and the young black male against the old black male, you must use the dark skin vs the light skin, you must use the female against the male. You must always have your servants and overseers distrust all Blacks.But it is necessary that your slaves trust and depend on us. Gentlemen, these are your keys to control and use them. Never miss an opportunity, my plan is guaranteed and the good thing about this plan is that if used intensely for one year, the slave will remain perpetually distrustful.
             &lt;/p>
        </item>
        <item>Augustus was one of the Roman emperors who influenced not only Rome but also played so many roles in maintaining peace with the other nations, who also had authority to the world .He grew up in a town southeast of Rome and he is said to had been adopted by his uncle (Julius Caesar) who became his father after the death of his biological father at his age of four.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            However, Augustus was not his name but rather Gaius Octavius, but due to his great influence as emperor, this name was given to him which signifies “a revered person”. It is also said that he did not take the name for himself and did not want to accept it initially but the senates and the people made it so. Augustus is a name derived from “augusta” which was a term used to describe sacred objects.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Augustus had lived a friendly life to maintain peace with his people but on the other hand, he was more concerned about his individual policies and intent for his rulership to subdue all nations and bring them under Roman Empire . He appealed to several situations logically and with authority to create emotion and life style without much worry, such as being threatened by others and loosing property to outsiders. Being the ruler of Rome for eleven times in a row was not something that ordinary man could do in those ancient days and even in this modern day, it is still difficult to have such rulership.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Moreover, he was kind to his senates and maintained a close relationship with them to the extent that his consoling words to Gallus Cyrenius convinced him to live after he(Gallus) had thought of committing suicide.  His effort to prove his faithfulness and commitment to his leadership as the Emperor of Rome, made him had the thought of taking the authority confined within his environment and colleagues, or was he pretending? It is said that all the proceeding emperors was all his relatives and as a fact , he sent her daughter to exile when he foreknew that she was sleeping with other influential men outside wedlock knowing that such was forbidden .
            &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            More so, the people of Rome would consider Augustus to be the “Greatest of the Emperors” due to his mandateto maintain economic stability and his support to the community when taxes fell short, inconjunction with his effort to overcome his rivals when they waged war thereby driving out the men who killed his father (AUGUSTUS,14 CE).
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            He also ordered the killing of his fiercest rival (Antony) despite his marital relationship with his sister.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            To some persons, Augustus’ leadership was indeed great to his people on the long run as he brought nations to submit. He drove out their rivals as well as maintained economic stability and peace. But we further observed that he could be characterized by individualism as he strived to keep Rome at the leading authority.  Although he permitted some nations to control small cities, he retained the power and controlled all the nations.
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Augustus was kind to those who followed his political standard,which this ideal leadership gained him the famous and memorable influence such that the month of August has to name after his given title/name.
             &lt;/p>&lt;br>
            Augustus:Augustus.The Deeds of the Divine Augustus.Retrieved from
            http://classics.mit.edu/Augustus/deed.html
             &lt;/br>&lt;br>
             Caaius Dio:Dio, C Roman History P.234.Retreived from
            http://penelope.uchicago.edu/Thayer/E/Roman/Texts/Cassius_Dio/53*.html
             &lt;/br>&lt;br>
            Soldier:Paterculus, V. The Roman History,p.239.Rtreived from
            http:/penelope.uchicago.edu/Thayer/E/Roman/Texts/Velleius_Paterculus/2C*.html\n

        </item>
        <item>&lt;b>Excerpt from Malcom X\`s speech entitled By Any Means Necessary &lt;/b> &lt;br/>
             &lt;p> A speech inspired by his departure from NOI( nation of Islam) to continue fighting for the liberation of black people in America, this time not under the philosophy of Islam but with anyone who was ready to bring about solution to the problems of millions of Negros( blacks) in  America.
            &lt;/p>&lt;p> &lt;b>Salaam Alaykum,&lt;/b>
             &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            Mr. moderator, our distinguished guests brothers and sisters when you live in a poor neighborhood you living in an area where you have to have poor schools when you have poor schools you have poor teachers when you have poor teachers you get a poor education and when you get a poor education you are destined to be a poor man and a poor woman the rest of your life. With your education you can only work on a poor paying job and the poor paying jobs enables you to live again in a poor neighborhood so it’s a very vicious cycle and usually these conditions result from the factors that Mr. Gray has pointed out as those who have absentee landlords, people who are rich live in downtown and let you and I live up here in the shacks (rough huts or homes) actually as a form of 20th century slavery.\n\n
            &lt;/p>&lt;p>
            I have to let the man know that we are peaceful people we are loving people we love everybody who love us, we are nonviolent with people who are nonviolent with us but we are not nonviolent with anyone who is violent with us, and now that I have the independence of action ,it is smy intention to everybody maybe to try and get some kind of immediate solution to the problems that are confronting our people I still believe the best thing for us to do is go back home to Africa but while we’re getting ready to go back, we’ve gotta eat now,  we’ve gotta sleep now we have to have some clothes now, our children have to do this so whatever kind of action program can be devised to get us to things that are ours by right, this is time for that kind of action. no matter what the action is i don’t think when a man is being criminally treated that some criminal has the right to tell that man what tactics to use to get the criminal off his back , I am going to use whatever necessary to get that criminal off my bed and the injustice that has been inflicted upon Negros in this country by Uncle Sam, ( A black man set by the white liberals to mislead the blacks into thinking that the whites care about them) In Georgia for your injustices ,the government is responsible for the injustices…
             &lt;/p>
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>